+1 303 800 6115 Brighton, CO, USA

Afshan Aman

Email: afshan.aman@gmail.com
Portfolio: https://afshanaman81.github.io
GitHub: https://github.com/afshanaman81

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/afshan-aman

Introduction

I am a skilled Software Engineer with over 7 years of international experience working in geographically and culturally diverse teams. I love to study, visualize and analyze socio-economic and spatial Data. I specialize in Full-stack and Front-end web application development using the MEVN (Mongo, Express, Vue, Node) stack. Over the years, I have acquired the following:

Specialties: Software Development; Full Stack (MEVN) Web Applications Development; Data Analysis and Visualization.

Primary Skills:

- Node.js/Express, Vue.js (v2), PostgreSQL, MongoDB, JavaScript (ES6+), jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, JSON, Bootstrap Secondary Skills:

- Java, C/C++, STATA, PHP/Laravel, Templating Engines (EJS, HBS)

Interpersonal Skills:

- Dedication, Honesty, Attention to Details, Organization & Time Management

Tools:

- GitHub, Webpack, AWS' S3, EC2, RDS, Elastic Beanstalk, QGIS, Matlab;

Work Experience

May 2012 – to Date Software Engineer | Team Lead New York University, Abu Dhabi, UAE

In a progressively responsible role, starting with research and data analysis, to becoming the senior Software Developer and finally the Tech Team Lead, my role involves resource coordination, people management and project planning and scheduling, in addition to the Full Stack web application development.

People and Project Management:

- Dividing high level project goals into achievable atomic tasks, Task definition & assignments, and making sure deadlines are met
- Deciding on tasks duration and their completion times
- Code Quality Assurance/Standards enforcement, & producing and maintaining documentation
- Gradually establishing protocols for CI/CD using GitHub and Jenkins.
- Gradually introducing agile project management methodologies to the whole team
- Training of team members to adopt the SCRUM practices
- Participating in recruitment of software developers and support staff

Software Development:

- Developing dynamic web applications using Node.js, Vue.js and MongoDB/PostgreSQL, for analysis and visualization of trading and spatial data in the field of agricultural and food production/transportation, collected using our Android Apps.
- Participating in gathering & understanding user requirements, designing database schemas and REST APIs, and designing the UI (user interface) and UX (user experience) for the Web applications.

Data Analysis:

 Studying large sized statistical, socio-economical, and spatial data either collected through surveys, specialized devices (such as sensors, accelerometers, drones) or smart phones applications (Apps), provided by partner

- agencies, or available on the web, using STATA, MATLAB, and ArcGIS/QGIS.
- Assisting the Principle Investigator in research by handling statistical data analysis of the mobility of migrant workers in the Middle East and Asia.

Jan 2010 – April 2011 Researcher University of Porto, Portugal

- Worked as a researcher in the field of Urban and Regional Transportation Systems and Planning,
- Studied the retail locations of selected sectors in the city of Oporto using spatial analysis and GIS for identifying interesting patterns and discovering and testing hypothesis.

Jan 2004-Sep 2004

Center Manager

United Nations Development Program, Peshawar, Pakistan

- Managed the development of Provincial Government Web Portal and establishment of District Citizen Information Centers (DCIC).
- Supervised the construction and renovation work for establishing the DCIC. Handled all correspondence with contractors.
- Supervised regular data collection, processing, analysis and dissemination of information at district level
- Handled Procurement activities for different sub-offices, developing IT related specifications, inviting and finalizing tenders and issuing inspection reports as a subject specialist.
- As part of a team of experienced statisticians and ICT specialists and young professionals, identified information needs of the DCIC project, designed a system, using ICT (Information and Communication Technologies) for improved transparency and accountability of state functionaries and access of citizens to information.

Education

2006 - 2008

Masters in Computer Science (Embedded Systems Informatics) **RWTH Aachen, Germany and University of Trento, Italy**

- A double-degree Master's program from two lead European universities
- Thesis Title: 'Efficient Implementation of a Simple Platoon Controller using a Rapid Control Prototyping System' which, simply put, is a longitudinal cruise controller, but in the context of a group of vehicles travelling together over a longer distance, such as a convoy of military vehicles or Cargo trucks.

Publications

'Experiences in designing a mobile GIS mapping tool for rural farmers in Ghana'. Proceedings of the 4th Annual Symposium on Computing for Development, 28:1-28:2 (2013)

Language Proficiencies

Main Language	Mother Tongue	Others (Read & Write)
English	Urdu, Pushto	German, Italian, Arabic

References

Prof. Yaw Nyarko New York University 19 West 4th Street Room 505 New York City, NY10012

Email: yaw.nyarko@nyu.edu
Web: www.nyarko.com

Africa House: www.nyu.edu/africahouse

Zohaib Jabbar

Senior Software Engineer Fund Recs, Ireland

Email: zohaib@fundrecs.com
Web: https://www.fundrecs.com